{
    "id": "b6583bbcac3f4c7cb5cb337ea7a360f8",
    "title": "If-Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If they had been more careful, this ……………………………..",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would / could / might have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not happen",
                "would not happen",
                "would not have happened"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6c169c6ead104b9195debc14f3d141cb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you …………………….. a little earlier, you could meet her.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "arrived",
                "had arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "88ad9a073a3245d3b50c1ccdf8c21d54"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………… faster, you could have overtaken him.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would / could / might have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "run",
                "ran",
                "had run"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "472eb808168b4c1f8ab01db43e8678d3"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you call me names again, I ……………………….. you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will hit",
                "would hit",
                "would have hit"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ce1035526a064f249df1f7998c65e6dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she didn’t mend her ways, she …………………………… in trouble.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "243bddc591874a8892fb46d275270fab"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had practiced well, you …………………………………. better performance.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would / could / might have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can deliver",
                "could deliver",
                "could have delivered"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "71f5a42b70d04672807bd6eb974c47e4"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………….. good care of your health, you will not fall ill often.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "take",
                "took",
                "had taken"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c45aa93062804213ba61341f7a94899e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ……………………………… a foreign language, she can find a better job.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "speaks",
                "spoke",
                "had spoken"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "289e14431ca540729d2f14ed3c5be396"
        },
        {
            "question": "If children ……………………….. adequate love and care during their formative years, they will develop behavior problems.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "do not receive",
                "did not receive",
                "had not received"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "24942c9f82e34974b617bbbe4e258147"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you learned your lessons regularly, you ………………………… higher marks.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "efdbb415eac4437c8f3a588c3902bee8"
        },
        {
            "question": "You will lose weight if you ………………………….. your consumption of fatty foods.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "reduce",
                "reduced",
                "had reduced"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b74e1afb6b2240ad8ef67157f6566eb1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………….. more money, I could buy a car.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "earn",
                "earned",
                "had earned"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bcb8f7cf5fee468eb5140276e4e76fda"
        }
    ]
}